(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-28T14:15:42.052730",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
なんであなたにはできないの
Why can't you do it?
なんてさ 陰口言われたり 諦められたり
People talk behind your back, give up on you...
好感度下がる 手際で
with your clumsy, unlikable ways.
電車は私を置き去りにしちゃうし
Trains leave me behind,
刃物野菜もスピード速すぎだね
and chopping vegetables is way too fast.
針の穴の数だけじゃ足りないんだ もう限界
The eye of a needle isn't enough, I'm at my limit.
毎日死ぬほど頑張って やっとここまで連れてきたんだ
Working to death every day, I finally brought myself this far.
あなたには分からない
You wouldn't understand,
わかってほしくない
and I don't want you to know.
きっとあなたにもできるはず
Surely you can do it too,
なんてさ 言うほど無責任にはなりたくない
I don't want to be so irresponsible as to say that.
それでも死ぬほど頑張って
Still, working to death,
かける迷い地獄はあると思った 投げ出したがる
I thought there was a doubting hell, wanting to throw it away.
悪くなるよ でも諦めたくはない
It gets worse, but I don't want to give up.
私の未来も
Not my future either.
失敗も全部渡したけの物
Even all the failures are things to pass on.
あなたには分からない
You wouldn't understand,
わかってほしくない
and I don't want you to know.
きっとあなたにもできるはず
Surely you can do it too,
なんてさ 言うほど無責任にはなりたくない
I don't want to be so irresponsible as to say that.
失敗も全部渡さないよ 傷つかない
I won't hand over all the failures, not getting hurt.
傷つかないでいて 可愛いだけの私でいい
Just don't get hurt, I'm fine being just cute.
見つかぞえたら 何書き足せ
If you count them, what should you add?
消えてしまうけど それと同じで
It fades away, but just like that,
君の顔ばかり 浮かべてた
I kept picturing your face.
髪型もメイクも奇抜で
Even with eccentric hair and makeup,
見た目で誤解される事ばかり
I'm always misunderstood by my appearance.
わかる人だけいればいい
It's fine if only those who understand me do,
いつもそうやって生きてきた
I've always lived that way.
小さい頃思い出せば
If I remember back to when I was little,
長い髪 自分で切ったり
Cutting my own long hair,
ママを随分驚かせてばかりの子だったっけ
I was always surprising Mom so much.
神様なんていないって
Saying there is no God,
しょうがないって
That it can't be helped,
笑ってみて
And trying to smile,
散々な目にあっても ちゃんと立ってるじゃない！
Even through terrible times, aren't I standing strong?
悲しい事があれば
If something sad happens,
一人で
Don't carry it
抱えてないで
All by yourself.
届けてくれればどんな事も受け止めるよ
If you reach out, I'll accept anything.
もっと real に wow wow wow yeah！
More real, wow wow wow yeah!
ほんとはあいつは笑わないって
People think he never laughs
冷たい奴と思われてるけど
And is a cold person, but
嬉しいことがあれば
When something happy happens,
それは自然にこぼれてくる
It naturally overflows.
最近 思い返せば
Lately, when I look back,
四葉のクローバーもらったとき
When I received a four-leaf clover,
なんだかちょっと 泣きそうなくらい
I was so happy I almost cried,
うれしかったっけ
For some reason.
神様なんていないって
Saying there is no God,
しょうがないって
That it can't be helped,
笑ってみて
And trying to smile,
散々な目にあっても ちゃんと立ってるじゃない！
Even through terrible times, aren't I standing strong?
悲しい事があれば
If something sad happens,
一人で
Don't carry it
抱えてないで
All by yourself.
届けてくれればどんな事も受け止めるよ
If you reach out, I'll accept anything.
もっと real に wow wow wow yeah！
More real, wow wow wow yeah!
無限大の愛だけど
It's infinite love, but
失敗だけど諦めない
Even when I fail, I won't give up.
まだ欲張りだから君と落ちていく
I'm still greedy, so I'll fall with you.
もうなかなか中々中中恋に落ちちゃって
Falling head over heels in love...
きゅっぴょ戻れない
I can't turn back anymore.
あれあれなんでふわふわと心が
Why is my heart floating so fluffy?
まだ熱くなるの
Still getting so hot?
なかなか中々中中君の引力で
Pulled by your gravity,
きゅっぴょ引き寄せて
Drawing me in tighter.
綺麗にそう覗いてるみたいでさ
It looks so pretty peeking in,
ねえキラキラな未来みたいなわからない
Hey, like a sparkling future, I don't know.
バーチャル リアル どっち可愛い？
Virtual or real, which is cuter?
バーチャル リアル どっちも可愛い！
Virtual and real, both are cute!
サムネタップはじめまして
Tapping the thumbnail, nice to meet you.
きゅんきゅんけしきたならはいどうぞって
Heart-throbbing and wiping it away, here you go.
数字は いつでもカムオン
Numbers, come on anytime.
一緒に踊ろうよ
Let's dance together!
あーね なお菓子食べたいけどダイエット中
Ah, right, I want to eat snacks, but I'm on a diet.
きみの好みにアップデート中
Updating to match your preferences.
ちりこしん きみとこうしんもっと推してほしいの
Marching on, updating with you, I want you to support me more!
バーチャル リアル どっちが好き？
Virtual or real, which do you like?
繋がる123次元 ポンと進んで飛び越えて
Connecting 1, 2, 3 dimensions, jumping right across.
いまやもっとリアルです ちくちくしないです
Now it's even more real, without any pricks.
ときめきちゃん ときめかげが続くストリート
Excitement-chan, a continuous street of thrills.
きゅっきゅっぴぴテレパシー 今日も配信
Kyukyuku pipi telepathy, streaming again today!
もっと語ってほしいの バーチャルリアル
I want you to talk more, virtual and real.
2とに1スピード足してきゅんきゅん
Adding speed to 2 and 1, heart-throbbing.
ピシてならて 手叩いて かちせいもん
Clapping hands, striking a pose.
えんじょいぜいも 一緒に踊ろうよ
Enjoying it, let's dance together!
あーね なんか会話1がんけど困惑中
Ah, right, conversation gets stuck, feeling confused.
ニュートンの不思議ことりさっち じゅきぴぴテレパシー今日も配信
Newton's mysterious discoveries, telepathy streaming today too.
もっと語ってほしいの
I want you to talk to me more!
ねえねえ どっち可愛い？
Hey hey, which is cuter?
どっち可愛い？
Which is cuter?
ねえねえ どっち可愛い？
Hey hey, which is cuter?
どっち可愛い？
Which is cuter?
どっち可愛い？ どっち可愛い？ どっち可愛い？
Which is cuter? Which is cuter? Which is cuter?
どっちも可愛い！
Both are cute!
お菓子食べたいけどダイエット中
I want to eat snacks, but I'm on a diet.
きみの好みにアップデート中
Updating to match your preferences.
ちりこしん きみとこうしんもっと推してほしいの
Marching on, updating with you, I want you to support me more!
もっと押してほしいの
I want you to push for me more!
バーチャル リアル どっちが好き？ どっちも好き！
Virtual or real, which do you like? I love both!
行くよ ふと忘れてしまいそうになるの
Let's go! I almost forget
昨日のあの記憶のピース
yesterday's puzzle pieces.
ねえ無くしたりはできそうもないけれど
Even though I probably couldn't bear to lose them,
うまく繋げばまた続きへ
if I connect them well, I'll reach the continuation.
でも今は関係ないんだよ
But none of that matters right now!
そんなことも忘れちゃえるような
In a mysterious world where I can forget even that,
不思議な世界にアクセル全開で
with the accelerator wide open,
飛び込もう it's show time
let's dive in, it's show time!
でもでも急ぎっパナシは禁物です
Still, rushing all the time is forbidden.
いつかが回ってるっていうぐらいじゃ
Just spinning around blindly...
だからたまにはゆっくり一休みしたら
So sometimes, take a nice, slow break.
それじゃちょっと早めのリズムで
Then with a slightly quicker rhythm,
止まれないぞ
There's no stopping now!
飛んでけ fly high
Fly high into the sky!
大きな息を吸ったら
Take a deep, big breath,
僕らの wow
and our wow...
ストーリーが今溢れ出すよ
Our story is overflowing right now!
もっともっと大きくね
Even bigger and louder,
最初が肝心なんです
the very beginning is crucial!
僕らが見ている遠い
The distant scenery we're looking at
白銀の前の景色で
before the silver snow...
実はちょっと昔らしい
Actually seems a bit nostalgic.
そう考えると不思議かもね
When you think about it, it's kind of strange.
そこにある予定でいて少しずつ違う日々を
Living days that are slightly different than planned,
過ごしてる
we spend our time.
きっと僕らの遠い線路
Surely, our distant railway tracks
隣の人のことを
about the person next to us,
一つも知らないけど分かんないまま日射して向かった
we knew nothing of, yet we headed toward the sunshine blindly.
もしも遥めの一歩もいいけど
Even if a distant step is fine too,
今はそんな場合じゃないわけじゃない
this isn't really the time for that, right?
あまてらてらすこの手で
With these hands illuminating the heavens,
触れて踊りましょう
let's touch and dance!
あまてらてらす光が差して
As the light shines down on the heavens,
あまてらてらす気風がさせて
with a spirited breeze across the sky,
あのね君だって
you know, even you
歌えるよ
can sing along!
誰にだって振り注いだ
Pouring down on everyone,
アップ前の
before the show starts,
光が差す方へ
toward where the light shines.
僕らは分かり合えない
We can never truly understand each other,
お互いの世界には誰も価値を付けられない
and no one can place a value on each other's worlds.
それでも隣で生きてたい
Even so, I want to live right by your side.
こんなに狭い星
On such a tiny star,
宝刀でも組んでさ歌いましょう
let's team up and sing together!
ずっと一人ぼっちはもう最後
Being all alone is finally over.
岩のように厚い雲をそっとと覗いた手を
Reaching out through thick clouds like stone,
握ってぐんで引っ張り出して
grabbing hold and pulling it out,
天を照らす光は淋しい記憶も
the light illuminating the skies heals even lonely memories,
同じように天を照らし出すから
shining up to the heavens just the same.
背中向けないで進むだけ
Don't turn your back, just keep moving forward!
天を照らすこの手で触れて踊りましょう
With hands illuminating the heavens, let's dance!
天を照らす気風がさせてあのね君だって
With a spirited breeze, you know, even you
歌えるよ
can sing along!
世界中のどんな朝もアップ前の
Every morning across the world, before the show,
光に満ちている
is filled with light.
大きどき返事はいいけど
Big, confident replies are great,
冗談なら笑えないよ
but if it's a joke, I can't laugh.
重大曖昧どきを夢中の
Lost in the heavy, ambiguous moments,
新機露に手を伸ばした
I reached out my hand toward the fresh dew.
ビ熱のよような日の物合ったり
Like a feverish day meeting another,
そんな光は見んなりしてだ
such lights gathered all together.
サワメグ子供を真似いかないで
Don't imitate the noisy children,
まぼろしじゃ嫌だよ
I don't want it to be an illusion!
私を呼んで
Call out for me!
魅惑のダンスインダスナイト広かって収まんないユニバ
Enchanting dance in dust night, expanding endlessly...
君の表情は私の知ら場所を
Your expression rewrites the places
書き換えて稼ぎね将来ね
I didn't know, securing our future.
一切が最高だったスタミヤダッシリ夢中になって楽しむや
Everything was amazing, getting totally lost in the fun!
行くよ？
Shall we go?
ふと忘れてしまいたくなる
Sometimes I just want to forget
昨日のあの記憶のピース
yesterday's memory pieces,
ねぇ無くしたりはできそうもないけれど うまく繋げばまた続きへ
though I can't lose them; if we connect them well, the story continues.
でも今は関係ないんだよ
But right now, none of that matters!
そんなことも忘れちゃえるような 不思議な世界にアクセス全開で
With full access to a magical world where you can forget all that,
飛び込もう it's show time！
Let's dive in, it's show time!
でもでも急ぎ足しは禁物です
But rushing is strictly forbidden,
いそがば回ってる？って言うくらいじゃん？
isn't it like "more haste, less speed"?
だからたまにはゆっくり一休みしたら
So if we take a slow break once in a while,
それじゃあちょため早めのリズムで 止まれないぜっ！
then with a slightly faster rhythm, we can't stop!
飛んでけ fly！（high！）
Fly away, fly! (High!)
大きく息を吸ったら
When we take a deep breath,
ボクらの（wow！）ストーリーが今溢れ出るよ
Our (wow!) story overflows right now!
もっともっと大きくね 最初が肝心なんです！
Bigger and bigger, the beginning is what matters most!
はじめまして、こんにちは！せーのでときのそらだよ！（yeah！）
Nice to meet you, hello! On three, it's Tokino Sora! (Yeah!)
も一ちょ fly！（high！）そら遠くまで届け
One more time, fly! (High!) Reach far into the sky!
ドキドキで（wow！）奇想天外に彩っていく dream☆story
Coloring the eccentric world with excitement (wow!), a dream☆story!
やっぱ1秒たりとも目を離さないで欲しいな
I want you not to take your eyes off for even a second,
瞬きもししてらんない
you can't even blink!
あっほらね最高でしょ？ー！ イエー！
Ah, see? Isn't this the best?! Yeah!
一歩進めばまた後ろへ
Take a step forward, then back again,
見えない力が邪魔をしている
an unseen force is getting in the way.
ジャンプしたりできたらいいけれど それも愛嬌、どうぞよろしく
It'd be nice if we could jump, but that's cute too, nice to meet you!
でも今は関係ないんだよ
But right now, none of that matters!
心響くリズムを辿れば
If we follow the rhythm echoing in our hearts,
不思議な世界の続きのページでまた出会えた destiny
We meet again on the next page of a magical world, destiny!
もしもし遅めのテンポも良いけれど
A slightly slower tempo is fine too,
今はそんな場合じゃないわけじゃない？
but isn't this not the time for that?
だけど大丈夫、一息つけたのなら
But it's okay, if you can catch your breath,
いちにのさんの合図で（いちにーのさん！）
on the signal of one, two, three! (One, two, three!)
飛んでけ fly！（high！）大きく声で叫んだら
Fly away, fly! (High!) When we shout out loud,
ボクらの（wow！）ストーリーが今紡がれてく
Our (wow!) story is being woven right now!
もっともっと大きくね ボリュームはmaxで
Bigger and bigger, with the volume at max!
はじめまして、こんにちは！せーのでときのそらだよ！（yeah！）
Nice to meet you, hello! On three, it's Tokino Sora! (Yeah!)
も一ちょ fly！（high！）そら遠くまで響け
One more time, fly! (High!) Resonate far into the sky!
はちゃめちゃで（wow！）摩訶不思議にきらめいていたんだ dream☆story
Glittering with chaotic (wow!) and miraculous wonder, a dream☆story!
やっぱ！1秒たりとも体感したいの
I really want to experience every single second!
クラクラしちゃうくらい
To the point of making me dizzy,
あっだけど最高じゃない？
ah, but isn't it the best?
ねぇねぇテンション高まってきて アテンション
Hey hey, tension is rising, attention!
ワクワク警報は鳴り止まない
The excitement alarm won't stop ringing!
ねぇねぇテンション高まってきて アテンション
Hey hey, tension is rising, attention!
誰も止められないわ！
No one can stop it!
飛んでけ fly！（high！）大きく息を吸ったら
Fly away, fly! (High!) When we take a deep breath,
ボクらの（wow！）ストーリーが今溢れ出るよ
Our (wow!) story overflows right now!
もっともっと大きくね 最初が肝心なんです！
Bigger and bigger, the beginning is what matters most!
これからもさ、よろしくねっ！せーのでときのそらだよ！（yeah！）
From now on too, nice to meet you! On three, it's Tokino Sora! (Yeah!)
さいこうに fly！（high！）そら遠くまで届け
Fly to the max! (High!) Reach far into the sky!
ドキドキで（wow！）奇想天外に彩っていく dream☆story
Coloring the eccentric world with excitement (wow!), a dream☆story!
やっぱ1秒たりとも目を離さないで欲しいな
I want you not to take your eyes off for even a second,
瞬きもしてらんない
you can't even blink!
あっほらね最高でしょ？ イエー！
Ah, see? Isn't this the best?! Yeah!
ひとつやめる時も
Shall we stop for a moment?
健やかなるときも
Even if times get peaceful,
愛を歌い続けることを誓います
I swear to keep singing my love.
困難や試練だって ダンスももっと突き進みます
So that we can get through every trial and dance together,
少しずつ押してもらえるアイドルになってみせます
Even if we get pushed around little by little, we'll become idols!
どのような不安な未来も 私が照らすんだ それでも落ち込んじゃう日は
Even so, on days when we feel down,
思い出しているよ みんなのその笑顔
We'll remember everyone's smiles.
未完成の地図を 輝きに変えて
Transforming an unfinished map into radiance,
誰にも真似できない 足跡を見せて
show them footsteps no one else can imitate!
見てて！
Watch me!
みんな！
Everyone!
走り出した願いは 加速してスピードを
The wishes we started running with accelerate in speed,
手に譲るものに この物語の 仮想世界だって
into whatever we entrust to our hands, even in this virtual world's story,
私が見えているんでしょ？
you can see me, right?
君だけにある世界が
The world that exists only for you
世界が ドキドキは 泣き出しくもなるよ
is a world where heartbeats can sometimes make you want to cry,
だけどドキドキが クレシェンドの足音 まだだから
but your heartbeats are still Crescendo's footsteps, so not yet—
大きくなって もっと 響かせて！
grow bigger, and make it resonate even more!
大きくなって だって 君に届けたいよ
Grow bigger, because I want to deliver it to you—
違うになって だって 未来を見に行こうよ
let's become different and go see the future together!
負けない夜なんて 光のダイアじゃないって
Nights where we don't lose aren't shining diamonds,
平気だよ 一緒に 笑いたいから 綺麗になって だって ちょっとの自信持って
it's fine, because I want to smile with you; let's become beautiful and have a little confidence!
手から芽だって やって ここで歌いたいよ
Sprouts from our hands—come on, I want to sing right here,
いつもよりも ちょっと 大きな声でもっと
even louder than usual, more and more
歪んで 進んでも 欲しかったんだよね？
distorted, even if we move forward, you wanted that, right?
声がちょっと ちっちゃいかも
Maybe my voice is a little too small?
スポットライト もっと当てて聞いてたいの頂上
I want the spotlight shone on me even more while I listen to the summit!
不安も全部 巻き込んで 上がるステージで
Swallowing up all anxieties too, on the stage we rise,
星のように 立って これが私のロックンロール
standing like stars—this is my rock 'n' roll!
君だけに 見せたいこの世界
This world I want to show only to you
ああ みんなと分かち合えるんだ
Ah, I can share this with everyone!
眩しい陽射しを背に 走り出す街の中
With the dazzling sunlight behind me, I run through the city streets
たそがれた いつものように肩を
As dusk falls, bumping shoulders like always
君に夢中なことに 理論なんてないのに
There's no reason why I'm so crazy about you
その腕は 絡むことはない
Yet your arms will never wrap around me
いつの間にか瞳奪われて始まった
Before I knew it, my eyes were stolen and it all began
離さない 揺るがない Crazy for you
I won't let go, I won't waver. Crazy for you
君が好きだと叫びたい 明日を変えてみよう
I want to shout out that I love you, let's change tomorrow
凍りついていく時間を ぶっ壊したい
I want to shatter the time that's freezing over
君が好きだと叫びたい 勇気で踏み出そう
I want to shout out that I love you, let's take a courageous step
この熱い想いを受け止めてほしい
I want you to accept these passionate feelings
ざわめいたフロアに にぎわうテーブル越し
Across the bustling floor and crowded tables
なんげない 君の視線に酔いしれ
I'm intoxicated by your casual gaze
恋をしているようで 踊らされてるような
It feels like I'm in love, or being danced around
高鳴る鼓動に もう嘘はつけない
My pounding heartbeat makes me unable to lie anymore
いつになれば変わる このもどかしい友情
When will this frustrating friendship change?
届けたい 確かめたい I take you away
I want to convey it, I want to confirm it. I take you away
君が好きだと叫びたい 何もかも脱ぎ捨て
I want to shout out that I love you, stripping away everything
心とかす言葉を見つけ出したい
I want to find the words that will melt my heart
君が好きだと叫びたい 今夜は帰さない
I want to shout out that I love you, I won't let you go tonight
見つめるだけの日々なんて 終わりにしよう
Let's put an end to the days of just staring at you
I wanna cry for you
ざわめいたフロアに にぎわうテーブル越し
Across the bustling floor and crowded tables
なんげない 君の視線に酔いしれ
I'm intoxicated by your casual gaze
恋をしているようで 踊らされてるような
It feels like I'm in love, or being danced around
高鳴る鼓動に もう嘘はつけない
My pounding heartbeat makes me unable to lie anymore
いつになれば変わる このもどかしい友情
When will this frustrating friendship change?
届けたい 確かめたい I take you away
I want to convey it, I want to confirm it. I take you away
君が好きだと叫びたい 何もかも脱ぎ捨て
I want to shout out that I love you, stripping away everything
心とかす言葉を見つけ出したい
I want to find the words that will melt my heart
君が好きだと叫びたい 今夜は帰さない
I want to shout out that I love you, I won't let you go tonight
見つめるだけの日々なんて 終わりにしよう
Let's put an end to the days of just staring at you
I wanna cry for you
君が好きだと叫びたい 明日を変えてみよう
I want to shout out that I love you, let's change tomorrow
凍りついていく時間を ぶっ壊したい
I want to shatter the time that's freezing over
君が好きだと叫びたい 勇気で踏み出そう
I want to shout out that I love you, let's take a courageous step
この熱い想いを受け止めてほしい
I want you to accept these passionate feelings
ざわめいたフロアに にぎわうテーブル越し
Across the bustling floor and crowded tables
なんげない 君の視線に酔いしれ
I'm intoxicated by your casual gaze
恋をしているようで 踊らされてるような
It feels like I'm in love, or being danced around
高鳴る鼓動に もう嘘はつけない
My pounding heartbeat makes me unable to lie anymore
いつになれば変わる このもどかしい友情
When will this frustrating friendship change?
届けたい 確かめたい I take you away
I want to convey it, I want to confirm it. I take you away
君が好きだと叫びたい 何もかも脱ぎ捨て
I want to shout out that I love you, stripping away everything
心とかす言葉を見つけ出したい
I want to find the words that will melt my heart
君が好きだと叫びたい 今夜は帰さない
I want to shout out that I love you, I won't let you go tonight
見つめるだけの日々なんて 終わりにしよう
Let's put an end to the days of just staring at you
I wanna cry for you
君が好きだと叫びたい 明日を変えてみよう
I want to shout out that I love you, let's change tomorrow
凍りついていく時間を ぶっ壊したい
I want to shatter the time that's freezing over
君が好きだと叫びたい 勇気で踏み出そう
I want to shout out that I love you, let's take a courageous step
この熱い想いを受け止めてほしい
I want you to accept these passionate feelings
ざわめいたフロアに にぎわうテーブル越し
Across the bustling floor and crowded tables
なんげない 君の視線に酔いしれ
I'm intoxicated by your casual gaze
恋をしているようで 踊らされてるような
It feels like I'm in love, or being danced around
高鳴る鼓動に もう嘘はつけない
My pounding heartbeat makes me unable to lie anymore
いつになれば変わる このもどかしい友情
When will this frustrating friendship change?
届けたい 確かめたい I take you away
I want to convey it, I want to confirm it. I take you away
君が好きだと叫びたい 何もかも脱ぎ捨て
I want to shout out that I love you, stripping away everything
心とかす言葉を見つけ出したい
I want to find the words that will melt my heart
君が好きだと叫びたい 今夜は帰さない
I want to shout out that I love you, I won't let you go tonight
見つめるだけの日々なんて 終わりにしよう
Let's put an end to the days of just staring at you
I wanna cry for you
パラパラ散る 火薬の匂い
Scattered scent of gunpowder,
セメント越えの春
Spring beyond the cement.
異常ナシ、私情アリ
No abnormalities, personal feelings present.
「戻らないでしょ」どうしても
"You won't return," no matter what.
穴ぼこだけの 愛 なんて
Love that's just full of holes...
ほら また 散る 火薬 の 匂い
Look, the scent of gunpowder scatters once more.
剥がれた現実と
Peeled reality
思考回路哨戒
and inspection of thinking circuits.
貴方はまだ夢のなか
You are still inside a dream,
砒毒を抱えたまま
holding arsenic poison.
あの日こぼした命の余りが
The leftover life we spilled that day
「ありがとう」などと呟いている
is murmuring things like "Thank you."
――ふざけんなよ もう息止められさ
---Cut the crap, let's stop breathing already.
さらば トーチカ
Farewell, pillbox.
「許してくれ」とは言わないが
I won't ask you to "forgive me,"
どうかその正義で僕を“吊るしてくれ”よ
but please, hang me with that justice of yours.
錯綜した終着点
The tangled terminal point,
お別れなのさ僕ら
it's farewell for us.
手向けた花と火薬の匂い
Dedicated flowers and the scent of gunpowder.
さらば トーチカ
Farewell, pillbox.
トーチカ
Pillbox.
相のうた
Song of love.
穴明け、埋め奈落と光
Punching holes, burying abyss and light,
セメント越えの春
spring beyond the cement.
私情ナシ、異常アリ
Personal feelings none, abnormality present.
目覚めた貴方に刺す現実
Reality piercing the awakened you.
ひとつの命を守る兵器が
The weapon protecting a single life
何百の果実噛み砕いてても
may be chewing up hundreds of fruits,
ひとつの心を繋ぐ決意が
and the determination linking a single heart
何千の火花をぶちまけても
may scatter thousands of sparks, but—
目覚めたひとつのその手の平が
the palm of that awakened hand
正義を“解ろう”と叫んでも
crying out to "understand" justice—
夢見るなよ 僕は逝き損ないさ
don't dream, I'm a botched departure.
だから トーチカ
Therefore, pillbox.
“解いてくれ”とは言わないが
I won't ask you to "untie me,"
どうかその毒で僕を枯らせてくれよ
but please, wither me away with that poison.
ああ グロリア 焼失点
Ah, Gloria, point of burnout.
お別れなのさ僕ら
It's farewell for us.
手向けた花は貴方の…
The dedicated flowers are yours...
だから どっちが
So whichever one
正しかろうと関係ないわ
is right doesn't matter,
どうかその兵器で僕をぶち抜いてよ
please pierce straight through me with that weapon.
期末の言葉が
Terminal words
“ありがとう”などと呟くもんだから
murmur things like "Thank you," so—
――ふざけんなよ
---Cut the crap,
もうさよならなんだよ
it's already goodbye.
トーチカ
Pillbox.
愛のうた
Song of love.
時代みたいに漂えば
If I drift like an era,
恐も恐もなかった
there was nothing to fear at all.
隅っこでまた君を探している
I'm searching for you again in the corner.
この声を聴かせてよ
Let me hear this voice of yours,
私に構って
pay attention to me.
惜しげなくよ恋の先を
Without reservation, beyond love,
広がって止まんない宇宙
an expanding, unstoppable universe.
その答えは私の中の将来までの
That answer is within me, up to the future,
かき混ぜた謎をすり寄せて呼んで
calling out by rubbing against the stirred-up mystery.
今が優しすぎて
Now is too gentle,
絡繰り合う道
a path of intertwined mechanisms.
神話は形を変えてく
Myths change their form,
次はサタネオン残す終点
next is the terminal left by Sataneon.
お別れなのさ僕ら
It's farewell for us,
手向けた花は貴方の…
the dedicated flowers are yours...
だから どっちが
So whichever one
正しかろうと関係ないわ
is right doesn't matter,
どうかその兵器で僕をぶち抜いてよ
please pierce straight through me with that weapon.
期末の言葉が
Terminal words
“ありがとう”などと呟くもんだから
murmur things like "Thank you," so—
――ふざけんなよ
---Cut the crap,
もうさよならなんだよ
it's already goodbye.
手をかましても離れないで
Even if you hold my hand, don't let go,
命、穿つ、我亭...
piercing life, my pavilion...
みなさん、新年あけまして！
Everyone, Happy New Year!
はーい、あけましておめでとーー！
Yay, Happy New Year!
盛り上がってますかー？
Are you getting hyped up?
みんなで協力して、優しい気持ちでライブできてるかにゃ？
Are you all cooperating and enjoying the live with kind hearts?
いいね、すばらしいよ！
That's great, wonderful!
みんな見えてるよ、今日はみんな青いんだね。
I can see everyone, everyone's wearing blue today.
そっかあれか、あのTシャツ、Tシャツが今来てくれてる人ーー！
Ah, right, those T-shirts, who's wearing that T-shirt right now?!
待って、当日券買ってくれた人っていますかー？
Wait, are there people here who bought same-day tickets?
すっか！ありがとうございますーー！
Is that so! Thank you so much!
すっごく感激した、ありがとうございます、本当に嬉しいです。
I was so deeply moved, thank you very much, I'm really happy.
てことでね、やりました、あれをやりましょうか。
So, we did it, shall we do that thing?
そうですね、遠くから来てくれた人ーー！
Let's see, everyone who came from far away!
海外から来てくれた人ーー！
People who came from overseas!
じゃあ、声は出さなくてもいい、あの、きょろきょろやるだけでもいいよ、女の子ーー！
Well, you don't have to speak, um, just looking around is fine too, girls!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
おおきに、ありがとうございます！
Thanks a lot, thank you very much!
ねえ、そして2階席！
Hey, and the second floor!
じゃあ、またペンライト回してちょうだい
Alright, spin your penlights again!
左の人緑ー！
People on the left, green!
右の人はじゃあオレンジ！
People on the right, then, orange!
じゃあ真ん中はあー！
And the middle, ah—!
みんな、今回はね、こんな感じでみんなも演出に参加しちゃうライブになっているよ。みんなで楽しんでいこうね！
Everyone, this time, it's a live show where you all participate in the production! Let's all have fun together!
今日はみんなも主役なんだー！
Today, everyone is the star!
惜しい！惜しい！惜しい！惜しいから！
So close! So close! So close! Because you were close!
夜はね、いっぱい動くと思って、ま、もう動いてるけど、昼から飲めばよかった。スポドリ一択！
I thought I'd move a lot at night—well, I'm already moving—I should've just drank from noon. Sports drink all the way!
がっつり、今年の目標みたいにムキムキになっていこうと思います。
I'm going to get super muscular like this year's goal, I think.
がんばれー！
Do your best!
じゃあ、初めての人ー！
Now, anyone here for the first time?
じゃあこれ、あ、着席してくれてありがとうございます。
So, um, thank you for sitting down.
1番最初のライブから全部来てるって人いる？
Are there people who've come to every single live since the very first one?
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
というわけでね、みんな分かったね。初めての人も、いつもお友達じゃない人と、そして昔から応援してくれる人、みんな集まって、みんながズッ友だ友達だよ！みんな楽しく過ごしていこうね！
So, you all get it now. First-timers, people who aren't usually friends, and people who've supported me for a long time, everyone gathered together—everyone's forever friends! Let's all spend a fun time together!
と、いうわけで、なんと、YouTubeでも無料配信......あ、まだ言ってないのに。
So, um, surprisingly, free streaming on YouTube... Ah, I wasn't supposed to say that yet.
まだ来たばかり？まだ来たばかりかと思うけど、続きは概要欄から......ええ、ええ、ええー！の人はどうしたらいいの？
You think you just got here? I guess you just got here, but the rest is in the description box... Eh, what should the people who go 'Eeeh!' do?
あ、コメント会場、配信会場のの人も楽しんでってね！わーい！
Ah, everyone in the comment venue and streaming venue, enjoy yourselves too! Yay!
それではもう1回飲んでから行くね。ちょっと水分も大事。
Well then, I'll take another drink before I go. Water is important too.
助かる！助けてくれてありがとう！
Saved! Thanks for helping me out!
では、次の曲も楽しんでいってね！
Now, please enjoy the next song too!
信じたい未来を今この手 掴みとるから
I'll grasp the future I want to believe in with these hands right now
諦める事はある意味早いのだ
It's still too early to give up
綺麗になる Burning Heart
Becoming beautiful, Burning Heart
もっと もっと輝けるわ Butterfly
I can shine even more and more, Butterfly
ネイルに新しいグロスで 退屈な日々
In a new dress, with new gloss, those dull days
変えたいの 君の為 自分の為に
I want to change them for you and for myself
届くかは 自分次第なら やってみせるわ
If it's up to me whether it reaches you, I'll show you what I can do
冒頭無料配信はこちらで終了です。
[Stream Notice: The free opening stream ends here.]
The free preview stream ends here.